myawesomebeauty.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy -

As you can imagine, you will find here our privacy policy, which is pretty much the same as most other websites. If you need any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, you are more than welcome to get in touch with us by email from[ our contact page](https://myawesomebeauty.com/contact-us/ "Contact us").

By visiting or using this website, you agree to the terms, policies and conditions set forth below. These terms can be updated at any time, so if you visit often please review them periodically to make sure you are still happy with them. Updated terms take effect immediately.

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://myawesomebeauty.com. We are a team of bloggers who happily work or used to work in the cosmetic industry.

At myawesomebeauty.com, we definitely consider the privacy of our readers or visitors to be extremely important. This privacy policy page describes in detail what personal information is collected and recorded by myawesomebeauty.com and how we use it.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

**Newsletter Subscriptions**

If you sign up for our Newsletter and/or  Updates you will be asked for your email address. Please rest assured that this is only used for our newsletter subscription and email updates. We will never share or sell this information to anyone. We have used a double opt-in subscription since the beginning of this website. This means you get an email to get you to confirm that you did subscribe to it yourself. You will need to click the link to authenticate this and confirm that you want to subscribe to our Newsletter and receive emails from us from time to time. As of May 22st 2018 we are using a new GDPR friendly sign-up form for greater clarity.

Once on our mailing list you will get some email updates containing news, blog posts, tips, special offers, promotions which includes or may be classified as marketing. By subscribing, you are agreeing that you are happy for us to send these emails.

Of course, as always, you are free to unsubscribe at any time from our Newsletters and emails as every email contains a link to unsubscribe at the bottom.

We use MailChimp to collect and store the contact details and send the Newsletters and email updates. Please read Mailchimps [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms of Use](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/). If you unsubscribe and wish to delete all records of your previous subscription contact Mailchimp or send us an email with the title ( unsubscribe) so we can remove them.

Any information like your email address is totally private and will not be sold or shared. Promise.

**Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

We will never add your email address to our Newsletter subscription without your permission. Nor will we sell or share your email address.

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, myawesomebeauty.com makes use of log files. These files merely logs visitors to the site – usually a standard procedure for hosting companies and a part of hosting services’s analytics. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. Of course, these details will never be shared or sold to anyone.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

→ Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on myawesomebeauty.com.  
→ Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our site’s visitors based upon their visit to myawesomebeauty.com and other sites on the Internet.  
→ Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

**Our Advertising Partners**

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include …….

  * Google
  * Commission Junction
  * Amazon
  * Widget Bucks
  * Adbrite
  * Clickbank
  * Linkshare
  * Yahoo! Publisher Network
  * Azoogle
  * Chitika
  * Kontera
  * TradeDoubler
  * ShareASale

_Please note each of these advertising partners has their own Privacy Policy for their site, so feel free to consult and check it for each of the advertising partners of myawesomebeauty.com._

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology in their respective advertisements and links that appear on myawesomebeauty.com and which are sent directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by our site’s third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see on the site.

myawesomebeauty.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

**Third Party Privacy Policies**

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. myawesomebeauty.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**Children’s Information**  
We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. myawesomebeauty.com does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian believes that myawesomebeauty.com has in its database the personally-identifiable information of a child under the age of 13, please contact us immediately (using the contact in the first paragraph) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include from time to time some embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

**Contact forms**

If you use the Contact form to send us an email,we will not use your email address for anything other than responding to you. Your email address is absolutley private and we will never sell or share it with anyone.

Data Used: If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the contact form submission data — IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message — is submitted to the [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. the site author who published the page on which the contact form resides). This email will include the submitter’s IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

**Analytics**

WordPress and third-party widgets/plugins and software used to operate this website may use information about visitors for analytics purposes. This could include your location, pages viewed, links clicked, downloaded files, pages or posts shared, how you came to this site and search terms for example. These are just website stats and are used anonymously. This is used to better understand our visitors, see what articles are popular and improve the content we create for you.

## How we protect your data

Our website has a SSL Certificate which means it is safer for you. If you have a look in your browser you will notice a green locked padlock symbol before the web address to show this. This means that all data you enter into our site is therefore processed with the secure SSL Certificate.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive a file with the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Compliance With Laws

We may collect, use, retain, and share your information if we have a good faith belief that it is reasonably necessary to: (a) respond to legal process or to government requests; (b) enforce our agreements, terms and policies; (c) prevent, investigate, and address fraud and other illegal activity, security, or technical issues; or (d) protect the rights, property, and safety of our visitors, newsletter subscribers or others.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. We use Akismet anti-spam software to keep our site spam free.

**Online Privacy Policy Only**  
This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our website and regarding information shared and/or collected there. This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than this website.

**Consent**  
By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.

**Update**  
This Privacy Policy was last updated on: Wednesday, May 23th, 2018.  
_Should we update, amend or make any changes to our privacy policy, those changes will be posted here._
